<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Romania on Varezers</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/romania/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Romania on Varezers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/romania/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss" />
    <item>
      <title>European Voluntary Service in Romania - a year of retrospect</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/evs-in-romania/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/evs-in-romania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is my personal recollection on my eight months spent in Romania, supposedly volunteering for environmental project for NGO. The project promised non-stop work for environment, planting, cleaning, educating, meeting youngsters and promote green living, but I had to be very adamant to get what I have been promised. Many reasons prompted me to do this, but mostly all the nice and sugary stories of other people I have red so much on the internet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture lessons in Organic Art Ranch, Romania</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/rachitele/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/rachitele/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;If only one human from every group that visits this place will get inspired, then the world will be a better place&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; /Roger says watching the campfire&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One lazy morning my friend Mariami rushes into my room and excitingly offers me a chance to visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://organicartranch.org&#34;&gt;Organic Art Ranch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;a place in the mountains where people do cool permaculture stuff&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; - can&#39;t say no to that offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/img/rachitele-seat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;on the way&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A week or so later, we set off to another daunting train Ride across quarter of Romania from Arad to Huedin, a village of 9000 people, where we pick up needed supplies we are expected to come with - some food and cardboard box. As there was no other way but to hitchhike, we wrote &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Răchițele&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; on our box and hiked along the road, anticipating of what&#39;s to come. On three cars we crossed all Mărgău commune into the Răchițele centre, a village of supposedly 836 people. It seemed just what we expected - a lot of mountains, confusing street behind a fence and no idea where to go. Fortunately, we got a lift from a neighbour of &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Casa Mexicanului&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;, how the locals like to call a place where foreign youngsters flock so much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
