<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essay on Varezers</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essay on Varezers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/essay/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss" />
    <item>
      <title>On adventuring</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/on-adventuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/on-adventuring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have extensively hitchhiked Baltic states, bench-marked in Norway, &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/evs-in-romania/&#34;&gt;lived and hitchhiked in Carpathians&lt;/a&gt;, traveled by train in the Balkans, &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/quest-for-the-stray-fox/&#34;&gt;hitchhiked 10% of circumference of the Earth from Riga to Madrid&lt;/a&gt;, worked in &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/rachitele/&#34;&gt;Romanian&lt;/a&gt; and Finnish farms, cycled the &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/camino-de-santiago/&#34;&gt;Camino de Santiago&lt;/a&gt; and filled my days with adventures. I think I can give some helpful advice on efficient, cheap and easy adventuring!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning&#34;&gt;Planning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is too easy to over-plan and over-pack but much more important is to stay flexible and light! Many people plan more than is humanly possible; returning angry, frustrated and disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camino de Santiago</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/camino-de-santiago/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/camino-de-santiago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;camino-preparations&#34;&gt;Camino preparations&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We felt tired of our routine and waddling through the same problems for past half a year, so we decided to go on an adventure! We agreed on Spain, for unknown reasons. It is kinda unexplored region &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/quest-for-the-stray-fox&#34;&gt;even after my first visit&lt;/a&gt; and Fox hadn&#39;t been to the north either, so it was undisputed compromise. I have heard of Camino de Santiago and really cherished idea of long distance cycling through unfamiliar terrain. I bribed the Fox with &lt;em&gt;old-lady-cycling the Camino&lt;/em&gt; youtube videos to accept the challenge! Less than a month until &lt;em&gt;the perfect dates&lt;/em&gt; we got cheap tickets from Riga to Barcelona both ways. Logroño has been chosen as the best starting point for our adventure and nobody had any objections. It just looked perfect on the map.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Voluntary Service in Romania - a year of retrospect</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/evs-in-romania/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/evs-in-romania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is my personal recollection on my eight months spent in Romania, supposedly volunteering for environmental project for NGO. The project promised non-stop work for environment, planting, cleaning, educating, meeting youngsters and promote green living, but I had to be very adamant to get what I have been promised. Many reasons prompted me to do this, but mostly all the nice and sugary stories of other people I have red so much on the internet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture lessons in Organic Art Ranch, Romania</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/rachitele/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/rachitele/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;If only one human from every group that visits this place will get inspired, then the world will be a better place&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; /Roger says watching the campfire&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One lazy morning my friend Mariami rushes into my room and excitingly offers me a chance to visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://organicartranch.org&#34;&gt;Organic Art Ranch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;a place in the mountains where people do cool permaculture stuff&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; - can&#39;t say no to that offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/img/rachitele-seat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;on the way&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A week or so later, we set off to another daunting train Ride across quarter of Romania from Arad to Huedin, a village of 9000 people, where we pick up needed supplies we are expected to come with - some food and cardboard box. As there was no other way but to hitchhike, we wrote &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Răchițele&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; on our box and hiked along the road, anticipating of what&#39;s to come. On three cars we crossed all Mărgău commune into the Răchițele centre, a village of supposedly 836 people. It seemed just what we expected - a lot of mountains, confusing street behind a fence and no idea where to go. Fortunately, we got a lift from a neighbour of &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Casa Mexicanului&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;, how the locals like to call a place where foreign youngsters flock so much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R12-U Soviet nuclear missile silo visit</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/r12u-nuclear-missile-silo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/r12u-nuclear-missile-silo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2011 I have visited few nuclear missile complexes for exploration purposes, but unfortunately our expedition failed. Yes, we got to see some 30 m deep missile silos and play with the echoes, but the command bunker was not accessible. Another complex was excavated and only one flooded missile socket was seen without a dome. This time we went to another complex and our trip ended in success. But for the start, I will explain what and why we visited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R12-U kodolraķešu bāzes apmeklējums Latvijā</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/r12u-kodolrakesu-baze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/r12u-kodolrakesu-baze/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2011 gada ziemā mēs apmeklējām R-12 raķešu bāzi, taču tas netika pienācīgi dokumentēts jo jaunie saimnieki pamatīgi pacentās visu padomju brīnumu likvidēt. Bija palikuši perimetra kontrolpunkti un viena neaizbērta raķešu palaišanas šahta bez kupola. Pēc Liepājas talkas apmeklējām vēl vienu R-14 raķešu bāzi, kura mūs sagaidīja jau ar vairākām raķešu palaišanas šahtām, taču kontroles bunkurs bija aizbērts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Šoreiz R-12U kodolraķešu palaišanas bunkurā sekmīgi iekļuvām un sākām pētīt objektu.&#xA;Tātad, no sākuma jāpastāsta par raķetēm. Padomju šķidrās degvielas vidējā rādiusa ballistiskā raķete bija 24 metrus gara, svēra 41 tonnas ar pilnu bāku. Tās maksimālais darbības rādiuss bija 2080 km. Raķete tika piepildīta ar degvielu īsi pirms palaišanas un kopā ar žiroskopa sagatavošanu bija kaujas gatavībā pēc aptuveni pusstundas uzreiz pēc aizsargkupola noņemšanas. Aizsargkupols - liels betona kupols tika noņemts ar domkratu un nobidījās pa sliedēm. Vēlāk katru raķeti palaida gaisā atsevišķi un katrai raķetei bija sava vadības pults.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viduslaiku cietokšņu anatomija</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/viduslaiku-cietok%C5%A1%C5%86u-anatomija/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/viduslaiku-cietok%C5%A1%C5%86u-anatomija/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Konspekts kopēts iz 2012. gada arhīviem. Visa informācija tika atrasta un tulkota no &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortress&#34;&gt;Vikipēdijas&lt;/a&gt;. Fona bildē ir daļa no Arad pilsētas cietokšņa Rumānijā&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jau labu laiku atpakaļ pamanīju cilvēku interesi par cietokšņiem un nolēmu apgaismot par cietokšņu uzbūvi, kāpēc tā vēsturiski veidojās, priekš kam tiem ir vajadzīgas tranšejas pilnas ar ūdeni un kā paspīdēt ar savām zināšanām nākamreiz, kad iesiet garām Bastejkalnam vai pāri Rīgas kanālam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cietoksnis&lt;/strong&gt; ir militāras konstrukcijas paredzētas pozīcijas aizsardzībai un cīņai. Cietokšņi un to daļas mainījās laika gaitā, jo evolucionēja arī ieroči, to efektivitāte uzlabojās, tika izgudroti arī jauni veidi kā tikt pāri vai cauri aizsardzībai. Cietokšņi evolucionēja aptuveni līdz 19. gadsimtam, kad no lielā mūra sienām palika vien tikai zemes valnis/uzbērums. Nav īsti skaidrs kad ko var saukt par cietoksni, jo to pašu vienu zemes uzbērumu ir grūti nosaukt par cietoksni, kaut arī tas ir evolucionējis cietoksnis, kamēr pilsētas mūris ir tikai daļa cietokšņa. Tad tiksim skaidrībā ar visu pēc kārtas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
