<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>essay on Varezers</title>
    <link>//varezers.org/tags/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in essay on Varezers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//varezers.org/tags/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On adventuring</title>
      <link>//varezers.org/on-adventuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//varezers.org/on-adventuring/</guid>
      <description>I have extensively hitchhiked Baltic states, bench-marked in Norway, lived and hitchhiked in Carpathians, traveled by train in the Balkans, hitchhiked 10% of circumference of the Earth from Riga to Madrid, worked in Romanian and Finnish farms, cycled the Camino de Santiago and filled my days with adventures. I think I can give some helpful advice on efficient, cheap and easy adventuring!
Planning It is too easy to over-plan and over-pack but much more important is to stay flexible and light!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camino de Santiago</title>
      <link>//varezers.org/camino-de-santiago/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//varezers.org/camino-de-santiago/</guid>
      <description>Camino preparations We felt tired of our routine and waddling through the same problems for past half a year, so we decided to go on an adventure! We agreed on Spain, for unknown reasons. It is kinda unexplored region even after my first visit and Fox hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to the north either, so it was undisputed compromise. I have heard of Camino de Santiago and really cherished idea of long distance cycling through unfamiliar terrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Voluntary Service in Romania - a year of retrospect</title>
      <link>//varezers.org/evs-in-romania/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//varezers.org/evs-in-romania/</guid>
      <description>This is my personal recollection on my eight months spent in Romania, supposedly volunteering for environmental project for NGO. The project promised non-stop work for environment, planting, cleaning, educating, meeting youngsters and promote green living, but I had to be very adamant to get what I have been promised. Many reasons prompted me to do this, but mostly all the nice and sugary stories of other people I have red so much on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permaculture lessons in Organic Art Ranch, Romania</title>
      <link>//varezers.org/rachitele/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//varezers.org/rachitele/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;If only one human from every group that visits this place will get inspired, then the world will be a better place&amp;rdquo; /Roger says watching the campfire
One lazy morning my friend Mariami rushes into my room and excitingly offers me a chance to visit Organic Art Ranch, &amp;ldquo;a place in the mountains where people do cool permaculture stuff&amp;rdquo; - can&amp;rsquo;t say no to that offer.
A week or so later, we set off to another daunting train Ride across quarter of Romania from Arad to Huedin, a village of 9000 people, where we pick up needed supplies we are expected to come with - some food and cardboard box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R12-U Soviet nuclear missile silo visit</title>
      <link>//varezers.org/r12u-nuclear-missile-silo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//varezers.org/r12u-nuclear-missile-silo/</guid>
      <description>In 2011 I have visited few nuclear missile complexes for exploration purposes, but unfortunately our expedition failed. Yes, we got to see some 30 m deep missile silos and play with the echoes, but the command bunker was not accessible. Another complex was excavated and only one flooded missile socket was seen without a dome. This time we went to another complex and our trip ended in success. But for the start, I will explain what and why we visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R12-U kodolraķešu bāzes apmeklējums Latvijā</title>
      <link>//varezers.org/r12u-kodolrakesu-baze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//varezers.org/r12u-kodolrakesu-baze/</guid>
      <description>2011 gada ziemā mēs apmeklējām R-12 raķešu bāzi, taču tas netika pienācīgi dokumentēts jo jaunie saimnieki pamatīgi pacentās visu padomju brīnumu likvidēt. Bija palikuši perimetra kontrolpunkti un viena neaizbērta raķešu palaišanas šahta bez kupola. Pēc Liepājas talkas apmeklējām vēl vienu R-14 raķešu bāzi, kura mūs sagaidīja jau ar vairākām raķešu palaišanas šahtām, taču kontroles bunkurs bija aizbērts.
Šoreiz R-12U kodolraķešu palaišanas bunkurā sekmīgi iekļuvām un sākām pētīt objektu. Tātad, no sākuma jāpastāsta par raķetēm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viduslaiku cietokšņu anatomija</title>
      <link>//varezers.org/viduslaiku-cietok%C5%A1%C5%86u-anatomija/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//varezers.org/viduslaiku-cietok%C5%A1%C5%86u-anatomija/</guid>
      <description>Konspekts kopēts iz 2012. gada arhīviem. Visa informācija tika atrasta un tulkota no Vikipēdijas. Fona bildē ir daļa no Arad pilsētas cietokšņa Rumānijā
Jau labu laiku atpakaļ pamanīju cilvēku interesi par cietokšņiem un nolēmu apgaismot par cietokšņu uzbūvi, kāpēc tā vēsturiski veidojās, priekš kam tiem ir vajadzīgas tranšejas pilnas ar ūdeni un kā paspīdēt ar savām zināšanām nākamreiz, kad iesiet garām Bastejkalnam vai pāri Rīgas kanālam.
Cietoksnis ir militāras konstrukcijas paredzētas pozīcijas aizsardzībai un cīņai.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>